The Scrapbook Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
The Scrapbook Collection
1931 - 1968
NPKMC-223-105
2 Linear Feet
Unknown
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
The Intercollegiate Rowing Association selected the Hudson River at Poughkeepsie as the site of their first Regatta. The Annual IRA Regatta was held in Poughkeepsie from the first competition in June of 1895 until the location was moved in 1949.
Collection Overview
The collection contains concert programs, playbills, newspaper clippings, postcards, telegrams, and photographs mounted in eleven scrapbooks spanning from 1931 to 1968.
The Scrapbook Collection was donated to the Marist College Archives and Special Collections by John Gartland Jr. Gartland served for three decades on Marist's board of trustees, beginning in 1969, was the adviser to three Marist Presidents, and was himself president of the McCann Foundation.
There are no nestrictions
Arrangement of the Collection
These records are organized into two series: 1) Concert Program Scrapbooks, and 2) Baseball Scrapbooks
Materials are arranged chronologically.
- 1. Concert Program Scrapbooks, 1; 1 linear foot 1 - 2 1 - 8
  Series contains eight bound volumes containing concert programs from The Dutchess County Musical Associated, Millbrook, Euterpe, The Music Department of Vassar College, The Dutchess County Philharmonic Orchestra, Broadway Productions, Carnegie Hall Performances, The Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra, and others. The scrapbooks also contain newspaper clippings that are related to the concerts and performers.
  Chronological
  - 1931-1937, 1 (Box 1)
  - 1938-1945, 2 (Box 1)
  - 1945-1950, 3 (Box 1)
  - 1950-1953, 4 (Box 1)
  - 1953-1956, 5 (Box 2)
  - 1956-1961, 6 (Box 2)
  - 1961-1965, 7 (Box 2)
  - 1965-1968, 8 (Box 2)
- 2. Baseball Scrapbooks, 2; 1 linear foot 3 - 4 9 - 11
  This series contains three bound volumes containing newspaper articles about Baseball, clippings entitled “Sportsman’s Digest,” cartoons, correspondence and photographs about Baseball. Many of the articles relate specifically Elmer Steele, who originally played 1st base for the Poughkeepsie Baseball team. The scrapbooks also contain telegrams and color postcards.
  - 1906-1907, 9 (Box 3)
  - 1907-1908, 10 (Box 3)
  - Elmer Steele, 11 (Box 4)